<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Rishab Dhar</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rishab Dhar</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 23:15:00 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implementing dependency injection in Flutter Application</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tech-write-up/flutter-di/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tech-write-up/flutter-di/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a Flutter budgeting application lately. Previously, I have encountered difficulties with effectively managing a variety of dependencies. Maintaining a clean and structured codebase is essential for any application that works with user data, many services, and complex financial computations. Dependency Injection (DI) is useful in this situation. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore how get_it can simplify DI in Flutter.
Why Dependency Injection Matters Dependency Injection is a design pattern that helps you manage dependencies in a more modular and scalable way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking a GoDaddy Domain to Netlify</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tech-write-up/custom-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tech-write-up/custom-domain/</guid>
      <description>This guide continues from Deploying a Blog Powered by Hugo to Netlify and will walk you through setting up a custom domain purchased from GoDaddy on Netlify.
Step 1: Purchase a Domain on GoDaddy Create a GoDaddy Account
Go to GoDaddy’s website. Click on &amp;ldquo;Sign In&amp;rdquo; at the top right corner or &amp;ldquo;Create an Account&amp;rdquo; if you don’t have one. Follow the prompts to set up your account. Search for Your Desired Domain</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a Blog Powered by Hugo to Netlify</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tech-write-up/deploy-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tech-write-up/deploy-hugo/</guid>
      <description>This guide explains how to set up a blog using Hugo and PaperMod, configure Netlify to deploy it, and link a custom domain to your Netlify site. You can also watch the step-by-step video by theplaybook on YouTube.
Install Hugo On MacOS :
brew install hugo On Windows :
choco install hugo On Linux :
sudo apt install hugo Create a New Site hugo new site portfolio -f yml Run hugo new site &amp;lt;site_name&amp;gt; to create a new Hugo site in the &amp;lt;site_name&amp;gt; directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolation in Postmodernity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/isolation-in-postmodernity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/isolation-in-postmodernity/</guid>
      <description>As I sit here surrounded by the glow of screens, I cannot help but feel a sense of isolation. In our world today, where technology connects us more than ever, it is easy to feel paradoxically disconnected. In this blog, I would like to share my perspective on why isolation feels more prevalent in this postmodern age.
Connection We all have a smartphone with internet connection. Social media apps like Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and X keep us in touch with our family, friends, and even strangers across the globe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questioning the Very Existence of Free Will</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/free-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/free-will/</guid>
      <description>What exactly is Free Will? To me, free will is the idea that we have the power of making choices that are not predetermined by the past or aren&amp;rsquo;t affected by external conditions. It&amp;rsquo;s the sense of having control over our actions and the ability to choose different possible paths.
The Illusion of Choice When I consider the possibility that my choies are not as free as I believe, I start to wonder whether free will really exists?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of Swarm Robotics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/swarm-robots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/swarm-robots/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Upon discovering the notion of swarm robotics, I&amp;rsquo;ve been bursting with enthusiasm (pun intended!). It seems like something straight out of a science fiction movie. But here&amp;rsquo;s the best part&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s not.
In this blog, we&amp;rsquo;ll be exploring the field of swarm robotics on how these tiny robots function, their applications and their possibilities.
Understanding Swarm Robotics According to ScienceDirect
The field of swarm robotics concerns the coordination of multirobot systems composed by a large number of robots, where the collective behavior emerges from simple local interaction among teammates and between the robots and the environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Afterlife</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/digital-afterlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/digital-afterlife/</guid>
      <description>It is always seemed to be a good reasoning to think of something worth to leave behind in the earth, something worth to change into it, the dreams we build, and the signs our presence leaves in the other people. What about in terms of other internetting it, however? This question has brought shivers in my spine as I think of my accounts on social media platforms with lots of sensitive and personal information uploaded on them and many more accounts that I own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello World! Welcome to my Portfolio. I&amp;rsquo;m Rishab Dhar from Assam, India.
Feel free to connect with me on LinkedIn to delve into my professional experiences and network with me.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a glimpse into who I am and what I do:
Personal Projects Education &amp;amp; Work Experience You can also access my detailed resume here
I am always open to new opportunities and collaborations. Feel free to reach out to me at rishabdhar12[at]gmail[dot]com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/</guid>
      <description>Bloc Ecommerce GITHUB = https://github.com/rishabdhar12/bloc_ecommerce/
Currently developing a feature-rich eCommerce application using Flutter, aiming to deliver a seamless and intuitive user experience across both iOS and Android platforms. Implementing BLoC (Business Logic Component) for efficient state management, to ensure a responsive and scalable application architecture. Following SOLID principles to maintain clean, modular, and maintainable code, enhancing the application&amp;rsquo;s flexibility and ease of future development. Commands Hive GITHUB = https://github.com/rishabdhar12/commands-hive/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Experience &amp; Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/work-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/work-experience/</guid>
      <description>Work Experience Beyond Imagination Technologies
📍 Remote 📅 September 2023 - Present 👩🏻‍💻 Sofware Developer Sapco IOT Pvt. Ltd.
📍 Kolkata, India 📅 June 2022 - July 2023 👩🏻‍💻 Mobile Application Developer TalkEng Online Learning Solutions Pvt. Ltd.
📍 Tripura, India 📅 August 2021 - May 2022 👩🏻‍💻 Software Developer Education ICFAI University
🎓 Graduate, B.Tech (Computer Science and Engineering) 📍 Tripura, India 📅 August 2017 - May 2021 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 1st post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/</guid>
      <description>Desc Text.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
