<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Rishab Dhar</title>
    <link>https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Rishab Dhar</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://rishabdhar.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://rishabdhar.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 23:15:00 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Historical Materialism</title>
      <link>https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/historical-materialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/historical-materialism/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Men make their own history, but they do not make it as they please; they do not make it under self-selected circumstances, but under circumstances existing already, given and transmitted from the past.&amp;rdquo; (Marx, 1852)
It might seem a bit contradictory at first—how can we create our own history when we&amp;rsquo;re limited by what’s happened before? But I think it really captures the essence of “historical materialism.” This concept, introduced by Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels, focuses on how societies develop not through random thoughts or actions of a few people, but through the real challenges and situations that everyone faces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Absurdity of Life</title>
      <link>https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/absurdity-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/absurdity-of-life/</guid>
      <description>Life is strange and full of surprises. At times, situations can be confusing and the harder we try to comprehend them, the more contradictory they appear. Either things go wrong or luck is not on your side. You and I aren&amp;rsquo;t the only ones, a lot of philosophers and thinkers have thought about it for generations.
Carl Sagan, an American astronomer, planetary scientist, and science communicator. puts it like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolation in Postmodernity</title>
      <link>https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/isolation-in-postmodernity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/isolation-in-postmodernity/</guid>
      <description>As I sit here surrounded by the glow of screens, I cannot help but feel a sense of isolation. In our world today, where technology connects us more than ever, it is easy to feel paradoxically disconnected. In this blog, I would like to share my perspective on why isolation feels more prevalent in this postmodern age.
Connection We all have a smartphone with internet connection. Social media apps like Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and X keep us in touch with our family, friends, and even strangers across the globe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questioning the Very Existence of Free Will</title>
      <link>https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/free-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/free-will/</guid>
      <description>What exactly is Free Will? To me, free will is the idea that we have the power of making choices that are not predetermined by the past or aren&amp;rsquo;t affected by external conditions. It&amp;rsquo;s the sense of having control over our actions and the ability to choose different possible paths.
The Illusion of Choice When I consider the possibility that my choies are not as free as I believe, I start to wonder whether free will really exists?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of Swarm Robotics</title>
      <link>https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/swarm-robots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/swarm-robots/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Upon discovering the notion of swarm robotics, I&amp;rsquo;ve been bursting with enthusiasm (pun intended!). It seems like something straight out of a science fiction movie. But here&amp;rsquo;s the best part&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s not.
In this blog, we&amp;rsquo;ll be exploring the field of swarm robotics on how these tiny robots function, their applications and their possibilities.
Understanding Swarm Robotics According to ScienceDirect
The field of swarm robotics concerns the coordination of multirobot systems composed by a large number of robots, where the collective behavior emerges from simple local interaction among teammates and between the robots and the environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Afterlife</title>
      <link>https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/digital-afterlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishabdhar.in/blogs/digital-afterlife/</guid>
      <description>It is always seemed to be a good reasoning to think of something worth to leave behind in the earth, something worth to change into it, the dreams we build, and the signs our presence leaves in the other people. What about in terms of other internetting it, however? This question has brought shivers in my spine as I think of my accounts on social media platforms with lots of sensitive and personal information uploaded on them and many more accounts that I own.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
